Guide to the Richard C. Carroll, Assistant and Associate Dean of Yale College, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Richard C. Carroll, assistant and associate dean of Yale College, records
1937-1972
RU 20
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
20
The records consist of the files of Richard C. Carroll, primarily from his positions as assistant and associate dean of Yale College from 1939 to 1968, including records relating to undergraduate activities and organizations, athletics, prizes and fellowships, residential college deans, the Council of Masters, the Course of Study Committee, and the Executive Committee. Also included are records relating to the Carnegie Teaching Fellowship program.
Yale College (1887- ). Dean's Office
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 9-B (YRG 9-B), Records of deputy, associate, and assistant deans of Yale College.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The records were transferred from Yale College, 1971; gift of Mrs. Richard Carroll, 1995.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the records is restricted. See Collection Contents for details.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by accession.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of the files of Richard C. Carroll, primarily from his positions as assistant and associate dean of Yale College from 1939 to 1968, including records relating to undergraduate activities and organizations, athletics, prizes and fellowships, residential college deans, the Council of Masters, the Course of Study Committee, and the Executive Committee. Also included are records relating to the Carnegie Teaching Fellowship program.
Deans (Education); Universities and colleges -- Administration; Carroll, Richard C.; Yale College (1887- ). Administration; Yale College (1887- ). Dean's Office; Yale University -- Administration; Yale University -- Awards; Yale University -- Funds and scholarships; Yale University -- Sports; Yale University -- Student housing; Yale University -- Students
- Records of the Associate Dean, Yale College, 1939-1972; Accession 1971-A-003
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2047
  - Correspondence and Subject Files, 1939-1968
    - Acceleration, 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Activities Budget, undergraduate, 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Admissions, Board of, 1952-1959 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Advanced Placement, 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Affairs, undergraduate
      - 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Affairs Budget, undergraduate, 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Affairs Budget Payment of Bills, undergraduate, 1966-1968 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - After Graduation (publication) (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Alumni Board, 1952-1967 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Alumni Music Committee, 1959-1963 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Amateur Athletic Union (MU), 1966 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - American Studies (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Andover Teaching Fellowship, 1960-1966 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Donald Annis Prize (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Anthropology (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Appointments (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Archives, Yale (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Amy ROTC (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Art and Architecture, 1965-1967 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Arts Festival (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Athletic Association
      - no date (Box 2, Folder 22)
      - 1958 (Box 2, Folder 23)
      - 1959-1961 (Box 2, Folder 24)
      - 1961-1962 (Box 2, Folder 25)
      - 1962-1963 (Box 2, Folder 26 - 27)
      - 1963-1964 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Athletic Association
      - 1964-1965 (Box 3, Folder 29)
      - 1965-1966 (Box 3, Folder 30)
      - 1966-1967 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Athletic Control, Board of: minutes
      - 1956-1959 (Box 3, Folder 32)
      - 1960 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Attendance (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Auditing
      - 1963-1965 (Box 3, Folder 35)
      - 1965-1966 (Box 3, Folder 36)
      - 1966-1967 (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Auditing, 1967-1968 (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - Audits, 1959-1963 (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - Automobile Registrations, 1966-1967 (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - Averages (Distribution of) (Box 4, Folder 41)
    - "A" Miscellaneous (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - Bach Society (Box 4, Folder 43)
    - Banner, Yale (Box 4, Folder 44)
    - Bellamy, F. Wilder, Jr. Prize (Box 4, Folder 45)
    - Biology Department (Box 4, Folder 46)
    - Bioscience Bulletins (Box 4, Folder 47)
    - Board of Admissions
      - 1959 (Box 4, Folder 48)
      - 1965-1967 (Box 4, Folder 49)
    - Branford College (Box 4, Folder 50)
    - Brown, Francis Gordon, Prize (Box 4, Folder 51)
    - Brown University (Box 4, Folder 52)
    - Budget: undergraduate activities
      - 1958-1962 (Box 4, Folder 53)
      - 1959-1960 (Box 4, Folder 54)
      - 1962-1963 (Box 4, Folder 55)
      - 1963-1964 (Box 4, Folder 56)
    - Budget: undergraduate activities
      - 1964-1965 (Box 5, Folder 57)
      - 1965-1966 (Box 5, Folder 58)
    - Bursar's Office (Box 5, Folder 59)
    - Bursary Committee (Box 5, Folder 60)
    - Bursary Staff, 1964-1966 (Box 5, Folder 61)
    - Bursary Staff, Dean's Office (Box 5, Folder 62)
    - "B" Miscellaneous
      - 1950-1964 (Box 5, Folder 63)
      - 1965-1968 (Box 5, Folder 64)
    - Calendar
      - no date (Box 5, Folder 65)
      - 1965-1969 (Box 5, Folder 66)
    - Calhoun College (Box 5, Folder 67)
    - California, University of (Berkeley) (Box 5, Folder 68)
    - Career Advisory Office (Box 5, Folder 69)
    - Challenge (Box 5, Folder 71)
    - Charter buses and flights (Box 5, Folder 72)
    - Cheating (Box 5, Folder 73)
    - Chemistry Department (Box 5, Folder 74)
    - Chi Psi Student Center, 1961 (Box 5, Folder 75)
    - Chicago - Yale Law School Scholarship (Box 5, Folder 76)
    - Civil Liberties Union (Box 5, Folder 77)
    - Class Gift Committee (Box 5, Folder 78)
    - Classics Department (Box 5, Folder 79)
    - "Coats and Ties" (Box 5, Folder 80)
    - College allocations
      - 1963-1964 (Box 6, Folder 81)
      - 1965-1966 (Box 6, Folder 82)
    - College Board Entrance Examinations (Box 6, Folder 83)
    - College credits
      - 1959-1967 (Box 6, Folder 84)
      - 1966-1967 (Box 6, Folder 85)
    - College Deans' (File) (Box 6, Folder 86)
    - College Deans
      - 1964-1965 (Box 6, Folder 87)
      - 1965-1966 (Box 6, Folder 88 - 89)
    - College Deans (Box 7, Folder 90)
    - College discussion groups (Box 7, Folder 91)
    - College Masters (Box 7, Folder 92)
    - College Prize Awards, 1961 (Box 7, Folder 93)
    - Columbia International Fellows Program (Box 7, Folder 94)
    - Columbia University (Box 7, Folder 95)
    - Comptroller's Office (Box 7, Folder 96)
    - Conferences (Box 7, Folder 97)
    - Co-op, Yale (Box 7, Folder 98)
    - Corinthian Yacht Club
      - 1963-1964 (Box 7, Folder 99)
      - 1964-1965 (Box 7, Folder 100)
    - Cornell University (Box 7, Folder 101)
    - Corning Glass Fellowship
      - 1965-1967 (Box 7, Folder 103)
      - no date (Box 7, Folder 104)
    - Correspondence, general (Box 8, Folder 105)
    - Council of Masters
      - 1955-1958 (Box 8, Folder 106)
      - 1958-1960 (Box 8, Folder 107)
      - 1960-1961 (Box 8, Folder 108)
      - 1961-1962 (Box 8, Folder 109)
      - 1962-1963 (Box 8, Folder 110)
    - Council of Masters
      - 1963-1964 (Box 9, Folder 111)
      - 1964-1965 (Box 9, Folder 112)
      - 1965-1966 (Box 9, Folder 113)
      - 1966-1967 (Box 9, Folder 114)
      - 1967-1968 (Box 9, Folder 115)
    - Counseling and Placement, Office of (Box 9, Folder 116)
    - Course appraisal form (Box 9, Folder 117)
    - Course changes, 1962-1967 (Box 9, Folder 118)
    - Course enrollments (Box 9, Folder 119)
    - Course of Study Committee: minutes
      - 1939-1941 (Box 10, Folder 120)
      - 1942-1943 (Box 10, Folder 121)
      - 1944 (Box 10, Folder 122)
      - 1945-1946 (Box 10, Folder 123)
      - 1947-1949 (Box 10, Folder 124)
      - 1949-1951 (Box 10, Folder 125)
      - 1953-1954 (Box 10, Folder 126)
    - Course of Study Committee: minutes, 1953-1954 (Box 11, Folder 127 - 128)
    - Course of Study Committee: minutes, 1954-1955 (Box 11, Folder 129)
    - Course of Study: general, 1954-1958 (Box 11, Folder 130)
    - Course of Study Committee: minutes
      - 1955-1956 (Box 11, Folder 131)
      - 1956-1957 (Box 11, Folder 132)
      - 1957-1958 (Box 11, Folder 133)
    - Course of Study Committee: minutes, 1958-1959 (Box 12, Folder 134)
    - Course of Study Committee, 1959- (Box 12, Folder 135)
    - Course of Study Committee: minutes, 1959-1960 (Box 12, Folder 136)
    - Course of Study Committee, 1960-1961 (Box 12, Folder 137)
    - Course of Study minutes
      - 1961-1962 (Box 12, Folder 138)
      - 1962-1963 (Box 12, Folder 139)
      - 1963-1964 (Box 12, Folder 140)
    - Course of Study Committee, 1964-1965 (Box 12, Folder 141)
    - Course of Study Committee
      - 1965-1966 (Box 13, Folder 142)
      - 1966-1967 (Box 13, Folder 143)
      - 1967-1968 (Box 13, Folder 144)
    - "C" Miscellaneous (Box 14, Folder 145)
    - Danforth Fellowship
      - 1961-1962 (Box 14, Folder 146)
      - 1962-1963 (Box 14, Folder 147)
      - 1963-1964 (Box 14, Folder 148)
      - 1964-1965 (Box 14, Folder 149 - 150)
      - 1966-1967 (Box 14, Folder 151)
    - Danforth Fellowship (Box 15, Folder 152)
    - Dartmouth College (Box 15, Folder 153)
    - Dean's Association, 1952-1959 (Box 15, Folder 154)
    - Dean's Honor List, 1955 (Box 15, Folder 155)
    - Dean's List, 1964 (Box 15, Folder 156)
    - Dean's Office (Box 15, Folder 157)
    - Deaths, action taken, etc. (Box 15, Folder 158)
    - Degrees (Box 15, Folder 159)
    - Departmental examinations (Box 15, Folder 160)
    - Dining Hall (Box 15, Folder 161)
    - Diploma (Box 15, Folder 162)
    - Directed Studies Program (Box 15, Folder 163)
    - Directory, Yale (Box 15, Folder 164)
    - Disciplinary Committee (Box 15, Folder 165)
    - Disciplinary Procedures, Committee on (Box 16, Folder 166)
    - Distributional requirements (Box 16, Folder 167)
    - Divinity School (Box 16, Folder 168)
    - Divisional IV, 1964-1965 (Box 16, Folder 169)
    - Divisional IV Major
      - 1965-1966 (Box 16, Folder 170)
      - 1966-1967 (Box 16, Folder 171)
    - Divisional Program IV (Special) (Box 16, Folder 172)
    - Divisional Honors Program (Box 16, Folder 173)
    - Divisional Programs (Box 16, Folder 174)
    - Draft letter (sample for readmits) (Box 16, Folder 175)
    - Drama at Yale, Undergraduate (Director) (Box 16, Folder 176)
    - Drama School (Box 16, Folder 177)
    - Dramat, 1961-1963 (Box 16, Folder 178)
    - Dramat, Yale, 1966-1967 (Box 16, Folder 179)
    - Dramat Association
      - 1964-1965 (Box 16, Folder 180)
      - 1965-1966 (Box 16, Folder 181)
    - Dramatic Association, Yale, 1967-1968 (Box 16, Folder 182)
    - Drugs (Box 17, Folder 183)
    - "B" Miscellaneous (Box 17, Folder 184)
    - Early Concentration, Class of 1968 (Box 17, Folder 185)
    - Early Concentration, Class of 1969 (Box 17, Folder 186)
    - Early Concentration, Class of 1970 (Box 17, Folder 187)
    - East Asian Studies (Box 17, Folder 188)
    - Economics Department (Box 17, Folder 189)
    - Educational Research, Office of
      - 1955-1959 (Box 17, Folder 190)
      - no date (Box 17, Folder 191)
    - Educational Television (Box 17, Folder 192)
    - Educational Testing Service (Box 17, Folder 193)
    - Eli International, Inc.
      - 1963-1964 (Box 17, Folder 194)
      - 1964-1965 (Box 17, Folder 195)
    - Eligibility Committee
      - 1951-1953 (Box 18, Folder 196)
      - 1959-1960 (Box 18, Folder 197)
      - 1960-1961 (Box 18, Folder 198)
      - 1961-1962 (Box 18, Folder 199)
      - 1962-1963 (Box 18, Folder 200)
    - Eligibility File -- part I, 1962-1963 (Box 18, Folder 201)
    - Eligibility File -- part II, 1962-1963 (Box 19, Folder 202)
    - Eligibility File -- part III, 1962-1963 (Box 19, Folder 203)
    - Eligibility Committee, Ivy
      - 1963-1964 (Box 19, Folder 204)
      - 1964-1965 (Box 19, Folder 205)
      - 1965-1966 (Box 19, Folder 206)
      - 1966-1967 (Box 19, Folder 207)
      - 1967-1968 (Box 19, Folder 208)
    - Eligibility Committee, Ivy #2, 1967-1968 (Box 20, Folder 209)
    - Eligibility, Yale Athletic (Box 20, Folder 210)
    - Engineering Association High Scholarship Prize, Yale (Box 20, Folder 211)
    - Engineering School (Box 20, Folder 212)
    - English Department (Box 20, Folder 213)
    - Enrollment in undergraduate courses (Box 20, Folder 214)
    - Essays (Box 20, Folder 215)
    - Estimated enrollment figures (Box 20, Folder 216)
    - Examinations (procedure and charges) (Box 20, Folder 217)
    - Exchange Program, Student (Box 20, Folder 218)
    - Executive Committee, 1958-1959 (Box 20, Folder 219)
    - Executive Committee minutes, 1959-1960 (Box 20, Folder 220)
    - Executive Committee, Yale College, 1959-1961 (Box 20, Folder 221)
    - Executive Committee, minutes
      - 1960-1961 (Box 20, Folder 222)
      - 1961-1962 (Box 20, Folder 223)
    - Executive Committee
      - 1961-1962 (Box 21, Folder 224)
      - 1962-1963 (Box 21, Folder 225 - 227)
      - 1963-1964 (Box 21, Folder 228 - 229)
      - 1964-1965 (Box 21, Folder 230 - 232)
      - 1965-1966 (Box 22, Folder 233)
      - 1965-1967 (Box 22, Folder 234)
      - 1966-1967 (Box 22, Folder 235)
    - Executive Committee, 1967-1968 (Box 22, Folder 236 - 237)
    - Executive Committee: general (Box 22, Folder 238)
    - Exemptions (Box 23, Folder 239)
    - Exemptions from final exams (senior) (Box 23, Folder 240)
    - Experiment in International Living (Box 23, Folder 241 - 242)
    - Extracurricular activities
      - 1962-1963 (Box 23, Folder 243)
      - 1963-1964 (Box 23, Folder 244)
    - Evening examinations (Box 23, Folder 245)
    - "E" Miscellaneous (Box 23, Folder 246)
    - Faculty (grades, instructions, etc.) (Box 23, Folder 247)
    - Faculty Graduation Meeting, June (Box 23, Folder 248)
    - Faculty Handbook (Box 23, Folder 249)
    - Fellowships
      - 1963-1964 (Box 23, Folder 250)
      - 1964-1965 (Box 23, Folder 251)
      - 1965-1966 (Box 23, Folder 252)
      - 1966-1967 (Box 23, Folder 253)
    - Fellowships, miscellaneous (Box 23, Folder 254)
    - Financial Aids Committee, 1959 (Box 23, Folder 255)
    - Five-Year Experimental B.A. (Box 23, Folder 256)
    - Football, varsity and freshman: academic ranks (Box 23, Folder 257)
    - Football halftime shows (Box 24, Folder 258)
    - Foreign Fellowships (Box 24, Folder 259 - 260)
    - Foreign students (Box 24, Folder 261)
    - Foreign Students, Committee on
      - 1964-1965 (Box 24, Folder 262)
      - 1965-1966 (Box 24, Folder 263)
    - Forestry School (Box 24, Folder 264)
    - Four-Course Program (Box 24, Folder 265)
    - Fraternities (IFC), 1962 (Box 24, Folder 266)
    - Fraternities
      - 1962-1963 (Box 24, Folder 267)
      - 1963-1964 (Box 24, Folder 268)
      - 1964-1965 (Box 24, Folder 269)
    - Freshman Activities Fund
      - 1964-1965 (Box 24, Folder 270)
      - 1965-1967 (Box 24, Folder 271)
    - Freshman Assembly (Box 24, Folder 272)
    - Freshman mailing, class of 1971 (Box 24, Folder 273)
    - Freshman mailing list (Box 24, Folder 274)
    - Freshman Year
      - 1957-1960 Aug (Box 24, Folder 275)
      - 1960 (Box 24, Folder 276)
    - Freshman Year report, 1962 (Box 24, Folder 277)
    - Freshman Year
      - 1964-1965 (Box 25, Folder 278)
      - 1965-1967 (Box 25, Folder 279)
    - Freshman: miscellaneous (Box 25, Folder 280)
    - Fulbright Committee
      - 1959-1961 (Box 25, Folder 281)
      - 1961-1962 (Box 25, Folder 282)
      - 1962-1963 (Box 25, Folder 283)
      - 1963-1964 (Box 25, Folder 284)
      - 1964-1965 (Box 25, Folder 285)
      - 1965-1966 (Box 25, Folder 286)
      - 1966-1967 (Box 25, Folder 287)
      - 1967-1968 (Box 25, Folder 288)
    - Fulbright Committee: general (Box 25, Folder 289)
    - "F" Miscellaneous (Box 25, Folder 290)
    - General warning lists, 1960 (Box 25, Folder 291)
    - General warning, warning and - per college deans (Box 25, Folder 292 - 293)
    - Geography Department (Box 26, Folder 294)
    - Geology Department (Box 26, Folder 295)
    - German Exchange Fellowship (Box 26, Folder 296)
    - Grade study (Box 26, Folder 297)
    - Grading system (Box 26, Folder 298)
    - Grading, Committee on (Box 26, Folder 299)
    - Graduate School (Box 26, Folder 300)
    - Graduate School and career advising (Box 26, Folder 301)
    - Graduation (Box 26, Folder 302)
    - Groton School (Box 26, Folder 304)
    - Guidelines, Committee on (Box 26, Folder 305)
    - "G" Miscellaneous (Box 26, Folder 306)
    - Hart Lyman Prize (Box 26, Folder 307)
    - Harvard, 1947-1959 (Box 26, Folder 308)
    - Harvard University, 1960 (Box 27, Folder 309)
    - Harvard House Plan (Box 27, Folder 310)
    - Harch Prize (Box 27, Folder 311)
    - Health Department (Box 27, Folder 312)
    - Heidelberg Scholarships and Committee (Box 27, Folder 313)
    - Henry Fellowships
      - 1962-1963 (Box 27, Folder 314)
      - 1963-1964 (Box 27, Folder 315)
      - 1964-1965 (Box 27, Folder 316)
      - 1965-1966 (Box 27, Folder 317)
    - Higher education and national affairs (Box 27, Folder 318)
    - History of Art Department (Box 27, Folder 319)
    - History Department (Box 27, Folder 320)
    - Honors (Box 27, Folder 321)
    - "H" Miscellaneous (Box 27, Folder 322)
    - Indiana University's fall semester in Finland and the Soviet Union (Box 28, Folder 323)
    - Infirmary (Box 28, Folder 324)
    - Institute of Far Eastern Languages (Box 28, Folder 325)
    - Institute of International Education (Box 28, Folder 326)
    - Intended Occupation Survey (Box 28, Folder 327)
    - Intercollege Athletics (Box 28, Folder 328)
    - Intercollege Council (Box 28, Folder 329)
    - International Honors Program (Box 28, Folder 330)
    - International Office (Box 28, Folder 331)
    - Internships (Box 28, Folder 332)
    - "I" Miscellaneous (Box 28, Folder 333)
    - Job applicants (Box 28, Folder 334)
    - Job opportunities (students) (Box 28, Folder 335)
    - Jonathan Edwards College (Box 28, Folder 336)
    - Junior Prom
      - 1957-1961 (Box 28, Folder 337)
      - 1962-1964 (Box 28, Folder 338)
    - Junior Science and Humanities Symposium (Box 28, Folder 339)
    - Junior Year Abroad
      - no date (Box 29, Folder 340)
      - 1965-1966 (Box 29, Folder 341)
      - 1966-1967 (Box 29, Folder 342)
      - 1967-1968 (Box 29, Folder 343)
    - Junior Year Abroad, Faculty Committee on (Box 29)
    - Junior Year in France (Box 29, Folder 344)
    - Junior Year in Germany (Box 29, Folder 345)
    - Junior Year in Italy (Box 29, Folder 346)
    - Junior Year in Scandinavia (Box 29, Folder 347)
    - Junior Year in South America (Box 29, Folder 348)
    - Junior Year in Spain (Box 30, Folder 349)
    - "J" Miscellaneous (Box 30, Folder 350)
    - Kennedy, J.F., Scholarship (Box 30, Folder 351)
    - Key, Yale (Box 30, Folder 352)
    - "K" Miscellaneous (general files) (Box 30, Folder 353)
    - Late degrees (Box 30, Folder 355)
    - Law School (Yale) (Box 30, Folder 356)
    - Library (Box 30, Folder 357)
    - Liquor (Box 30, Folder 358)
    - Liquor Commission, State (Box 30, Folder 359)
    - Lists, Miscellaneous (veterans, etc.) (Box 30, Folder 360)
    - Yale Literary Magazine (Box 30, Folder 361)
    - Yale Literary (current) (Box 30, Folder 362)
    - Lockpicking (Box 30, Folder 363)
    - "L" Miscellaneous (Box 30, Folder 364)
    - M.A. - B.A. program (Box 30, Folder 365)
    - Majors (enrollment), 1958 (Box 30, Folder 366)
    - Marshall, Margaret Laughlin Fellowship (Box 30, Folder 368)
    - Marshall Scholarships (Box 30, Folder 369)
    - Marshall Scholarships (British) (Box 30, Folder 370)
    - Mathematics Department (Box 31, Folder 371)
    - Meacham Scholarship (Box 31, Folder 372)
    - Meal contracts (Box 31, Folder 373)
    - Medical School (Box 31, Folder 374)
    - Meeker, J. Edward, Prize (Box 31, Folder 375)
    - Memorandums - office procedures, etc. (Box 31, Folder 376)
    - Military Science Department (Box 31, Folder 377)
    - Military Service Office (Yale) (Box 31, Folder 378)
    - Mississippi Summer Project (Box 31, Folder 379)
    - Mory's Scholarship (Box 31, Folder 380)
    - Music School (Box 31, Folder 381)
    - "M" Miscellaneous (Box 31, Folder 382)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 31, Folder 383)
    - National Association of Student Personnel Administrators (Box 31, Folder 384)
    - National Collegiate Athletic Association, 1949-1959 (Box 31, Folder 385)
    - N.C.A.A., 1962-1967 (Box 32, Folder 386)
    - N.C.A.A.: fellowships (Box 32, Folder 387)
    - N.C.A.A.: graduate scholarship (Box 32, Folder 388)
    - National Cultural Network (Box 32, Folder 389)
    - National Science Foundation (Box 32, Folder 390)
    - National Student Association (Box 32, Folder 391)
    - C.F. Natunewicz: correspondence, 1965-1966 (Box 32, Folder 392 - 393)
    - Naval Science, 1956-1959 (Box 33, Folder 394)
    - News Bureau: releases (Box 33, Folder 395)
    - Newsletters (Box 33, Folder 396)
    - Noble Fellowship
      - 1958 (Box 33, Folder 398)
      - 1965-1966 (Box 33, Folder 399)
      - 1966-1967 (Box 33, Folder 400)
    - Non-graduates - Class of 1964 (Box 33, Folder 401)
    - Non-residents (Box 33, Folder 402)
    - "N" Miscellaneous (Box 33, Folder 403)
    - Occupations, intended (Box 33, Folder 404)
    - Off-campus living: requests (Box 33, Folder 405)
    - Office: hold (Box 33, Folder 406)
    - Office personnel (Box 33, Folder 407)
    - Office personnel
      - 1965-1966 (Box 34, Folder 408)
      - 1966-1967 (Box 34, Folder 409)
    - "Operation Impetus" (Box 34, Folder 410)
    - Orwell Forum (Box 34, Folder 411)
    - Outdoor recreation (Box 34, Folder 412)
    - "O" Miscellaneous (Box 34, Folder 413)
    - Parents' Day (Box 34, Folder 414)
    - Parietal rules
      - no date (Box 34, Folder 415)
      - 1965-1967 (Box 34, Folder 416)
    - Parietals, 1968 (Box 34, Folder 417)
    - Peace Corps (Box 34, Folder 418)
    - Pennsylvania, University of (Box 34, Folder 419)
    - Phi Beta Kappa (Box 34, Folder 420)
    - Philosophy Department (Box 34, Folder 421)
    - Physical Education (Box 34, Folder 422)
    - Physics Department (Box 34, Folder 423)
    - Pierson College (Box 34, Folder 424)
    - Placement News, Yale (Box 34, Folder 425)
    - Placement Officers: for Freshmen (Box 34, Folder 426)
    - Placement tests (Box 34, Folder 427)
    - Plagiarism and paper writing (Box 34, Folder 428)
    - Political Science Department (Box 34, Folder 429)
    - Political Union
      - no date (Box 35, Folder 430)
      - 1964-1965 (Box 35, Folder 431)
    - Post Graduate Opportunities, Committee on (Box 35, Folder 432)
    - Pre-Law Advisory Program
      - no date (Box 35, Folder 433)
      - 1965-1966 (Box 35, Folder 434)
      - 1966-1967 (Box 35, Folder 435)
    - Premedical (Box 35, Folder 436)
    - President's Committee on Dining Halls (Box 35, Folder 437)
    - President's Office (Box 35, Folder 438)
    - Princeton (Box 35, Folder 439)
    - Prizes (Box 35, Folder 440 - 441)
    - Profiles of the classes of 1965 (Box 35, Folder 442)
    - Programs of Study, Yale College (Box 35, Folder 443)
    - Prom, Senior, 1963-1964 (Box 35, Folder 444)
    - Prom, the Yale, 1964-1965 (Box 35, Folder 445)
    - Prom, Senior, 1966 (Box 35, Folder 446)
    - Prom, Yale, 1966-1968 (Box 35, Folder 447)
    - Prom, Senior, 1967-1968 (Box 35, Folder 448)
    - Prospective Students (Freshmen) (Box 35, Folder 449)
    - Provo (Box 35, Folder 450)
    - Psychology Department (Box 35, Folder 451)
    - Psychology Experiments (Box 35, Folder 452)
    - "P" Miscellaneous (Box 35, Folder 453)
    - "Q" Miscellaneous (Box 35, Folder 454)
    - Readmissions (Box 35, Folder 456)
    - Recommendations (Box 35, Folder 457)
    - Record, Yale (Box 36, Folder 458)